

BUI VAN BINH

07/03/2000

Data Scientist

Phone: +84 375 070 743

E-mail: bvbinh1362@gmail.com

Address: 96/26 Ton Dan, Dist. 4, HCMC.

I am a self-taught Data Science enthusiast who first took interest in the field back in 2020. Since then, I have explored various aspects of Data Science such as ML/DL, Big Data frameworks, storytelling, statistical learning, ...

After several years of working as well as studying practical data in both technical and operational perspective, I decide to devote myself to a technical role which can give me more hands-on experience and achievements, so I am looking for an opportunity to fulfill this desire.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Commercial Excellence Specialist (03/2023 – now)

B. Braun Vietnam Co., Ltd

- Salesforce.com and internal data administrator:
 - Maintaining the availability and quality of customer data, sales logs, sales opportunities data, ... and give out analyses or reports as required from stakeholders.
 - Participating in KPIs designing for system performance and the workflow of sales tracking.
 - Planning the implementation of operational digitalization projects from regional and global management.
- Process monthly sales, stock, tender,... report from dealers/distributors:
 - Manipulating the data received.
 - Cross-checking with data from other departments (warehouses, sales team,...)
- Managing and building Power BI Reports:
 - Building dashboard and administrator the access for other users.
- Researching market data from third party.
- Supporting other ad hoc tasks related to data and reporting.

Data Analyst (06/2022 – 02/2023)

VTECS-HOLDINGS Co., Ltd

- Building product features:
 - Researching suitable framework and programing the features for web services.
 - Optimizing the features according to feedback from customers.
- Conducting ETL for raw data from customers.
- Writing and maintain SQL Stored Procedures for web APIs.
- o Taking part in defining database schema, data structures and pipelines,...

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

Data Science & Machine Learning Certificate (01/2024 – 12/2024)

Computer Science Centre – University of Science – VNUHCM

An 1-year course with many modules specializing in different aspects of Data Science such as data structure & visualization, data analytics, machine learning, big data,...

Bachelor's Degree of E-commerce (08/2018 – 08/2022)

University of Economics and Law - VNUHCM

Academic IELTS 7.0 Certificate – British Council (2018)

SKILLS & TOOLS

- Problem-solving
- Researching & Self-learning
- Data Analytics & Engineering
- Programming mindset

- Applied Statistics & Maths
- Python
- Power BI & MS Excel
- RBDMS

HANDS-ON PROJECTS

Vietnamese Sentimental Analysis with *underthesea* module.

Product Recommender System with SVD.

Customer Segmentation with K-means.

School Timetable Scheduling with Genetics algorithm.

Google Stock Price Prediction using LSTM.